

(v) live:programdev0001

M bashpog@gmail.com

Shchuchinsk, Kazakhstan

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Design
Kazakh Academy of Transport
& Communication
2012 - 2016

EXPERTISE

Backend

Web design

Data analysis

SEO

LANGUAGE

English

BASHIR POGOROV

Mobile & Website developer

ABOUT ME

I'm a principal Lead Web and Mobile Application Developer with a strong background in design and systems engineering and over 9 years of experience as an Information Technology professional.

I possess specific experience with Internet networking and protocols, digital graphic arts/layout, web applications development, cross-platform communications/development, enterprise application develop.

- 4+ Years of Web Developer Experience
- 2+Years of Mobile Developer Experience
- Over 3+ years of Experience in the areas this includes Requirement Analysis, Development, Testing, Implementation and Maintenance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

O Jul 2021- Present Invatu Technology | Dubai

Senior software developer

- Expertise in developing highly interactive rich Web UI using HTML, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap.
- Excellent experience in creating REST Webservice using Spring BOOT (Rest Controller, JSON, Mappings, Data Formats, Swagger, Filtering, Versioning, Authentication, Data JPA).

o 2019 - 2021

Freelancer

- full-stack developer with approximately 7 years of experience of extensive backend skills
- Experience in data validation of various sources like Teradata, DB2, Informix, Oracle, SQL Server and Sybase.
- Adding new features and improving user experience while employing ReactJS, Flux, TypeScript, ES6, WebPack, and NodeJS kept me busy there.

o 2017 - 2019

IT-Attractor | Kazaustan

data analysis

Developed Python scripts to automate data validation and data cleaning processes such as deduplicating and checking data consistency using Pandas and Apache Airflow.